Guide to the Francis P. Squibb Papers 1894-2003
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Printed and Handwritten Music
  - Sheet Music, "The 20th Century Rag," Grant Clarke and Edgar Leslie, music by Maurice Abrahams; Maurice Abrahams Music Co., 1914 "29th & Dearborn," Richard M. Jones, arranged by Elmer Schoebel; Melrose Bros., 1925 "African Pas'," Maurice Kirwin, 1902 "The Alcoholic Blues (Some Blues)," Edward Laska, music by Albert Von Tilzer; Broadway Music Corporation, 1919 "All Aboard For Dixie Land," Jack Yellen, music by George L. Cobb; Jerome H. Remick & Company, 1914 "American Beauty," Harry Zickel; Kalamazoo Corset Co., 1908 "American Jubilee," Edward B. Claypoole; Broadway Music Corporation, 1916 "Any Old Rag," Richard Goosman; Charles I. Davis Music Publisher, 1909 "The Arrow Dance," Arthur M. Cohen; H.A. Eveleth, 1894 "At a Georgia Campmeeting," Kerry Mills; F.A. Mills, 1897 "At the Yiddish Wedding Jubilee," Joe McCarthy, Jack Glogau, and Al. Paintadosi; Leo Feist, Inc., 1914 "Beale Street Blues," W.C. Handy, arranged by J. Lawrence Cook; Pace and Handy Music Company, 1935 "Behave Yourself," Roy Bargy; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1922 "Bird of Paradise," Duke Ellington; Robbins Music Corporation, 1935 "The Birth of A Nation," Joseph Carl Breil; Chappell & Company, 1916 "Black and White Rag," George Botsford; Jerome H. Remick, 1913 "Blue Prelude," Gordon Jenkins, music by Joe Bishop; Isham Jones Inc., 1933 "Blue Thoughts," Eubie Blake; Handy Brothers Music Company, 1935 "A Blues Serenade," Frank Signorelli, Vincent Grande, and Jimmy Lytell; Mills Music Inc., 1927 "Bluin' the Black Keys," Arthur Schutt; Robbins Music Corporation, 1926 "Bohemia Rag," Joseph F. Lamb; Stark Music Company, 1919 "Bouncing on the Keys," Edward Claypoole; Jack Mills Inc, 1924 "Brain-Storm Rag," Bud Manchester; Stark Music Printing, 1907 "Bugle Blues," Count Basie; Bregman, Vocco, and Conn, 1943 "The Bully Rag," J. Fred O'Connor; F.A. Mills, 1910 "The Burning of Rome," E.T. Paull; E.T. Paull, 1903 "The Cake Walk in the Sky," Ben. Harney; M. Witmark and Sons, 1899 "Calico Rag," Nat. Johnson; F.J.A. Forster, 1914 "Cannon Ball," Jos. C. Northup, arranged by Thos. R. Confare; Harold Rossiter Music Company, 1905 "Cannon Ball," Jos. C. Northup, arranged by Thos. R. Confare; Harold Rossiter Music Company, 1905 "Casa Loma Stomp," H. Eugene Gifford; Mayfair Music Corporation, 1934 "Cataract Rag," Robert Hampton; Stark Music Company, 1914 "Chanticleer (Cock-a-doodle-doo) Rag," Albert Gumble; Jerome H. Remick and Company, 1910 "Charley My Boy," Gus Kahn and Ted Fiorito; Irving Berlin Inc., 1924 "The Chief's March," Harry Appel; Howley, Haviland, & Co., 1900 "Chimes Blues," Joseph Oliver; Melrose Brothers Music Company, 1923 "Chopin's Ghost," Bert Shefter; Joe Davis, Inc., 1937 "Chopinata," Clement Doucet; Editions Musicales, 1927 "Chromatic Rag," Will Held; Melrose Brothers Music Company, 1916 "Cole Smoak," Clarence H. St. John; Stark Music Company, 1906 "Creole Belles," J. Bodewalt Lampe; Whitney-Warner Publishing Company, 1900 "Dance of the Golden Rods," John J. Fitzpatrick; De Luxe Music Company, 1908 "Deuces Wild," Mary Lou Williams; Robbins Music Corporation, 1944 "Dixie Darlings," Percy Wenrich; Jerry Vogel Music Company, 1935 "Dream Rag," Jessie Picket; Eubie Blake, undated "Dream Rag," Jessie Picket; Eubie Blake, undated "The Duke 'Falls In'," Donald Heywood; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music, "Eli Green's Cake Walk," Dave Reed Jr., music by Sadie Koninsky; Jos. W. Stern and Company, 1896 "Entertainer's Rag," Jay Roberts; Forster Music Publisher, 1912 "Entertainer's Rag," Jay Roberts; Forster Music Publisher, 1912 "Excelsior," Joseph Lamb; Stark Music Company, 1909 "Excelsior," Joseph Lamb; Stark Music Company, 1909 "Fickle Fay Creep," Harrison Smith and Ben Garrison; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1950 "Floreine Waltz," Ernest J. Schuster, arranged by Warner C. Williams; Warner C. Williams and Company, 1909 "Good Gravy Rag," Harry Belding; Vogel Music Company, 1926 "A Good Time Girl," N.L.H; J. W. Stewart and Company, 1909 "Hot-House Rag," Paul Pratt; Melrose Brothers Music Company, 1914 "I Got a Rock," Blanche Merrill; Chas. K. Harris, 1911 "I'd Like to See the Kaiser with a Lily in his Hand," Henry Lewis, Howard Johnson, and Billy Frisch; Leo Feist, Inc., 1918 "I'm Looking for a Little Bluebird (To Cheer Me Up With a Little Song)," Harrison Smith, music by Ben Garrison; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1949 "I'm Tired," William Jerome, music by Jean Schwartz; Shapiro, Bernstein, and Von Tilzer, 1901 "Ice and Snow (or Don't Leave Me in the Ice and Snow)," Tony Jackson; Will Rossiter, 1917 "(Gee, I'd be Happy) If Someone Would Only Love Me," Harrison Smith, music by Ben Garrison; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1950 "Intermission Rag," Charles Wellinger; Roger Graham Music Publisher, 1916 "Jazz Baby," Blance Merrill, music by M.K. Jerome; Waterson, Berlin, and Snyder Company, 1919 "Jazzapation," Edward B. Claypool; Jerome H. Remick and Company, 1920 "Jim Jams," Roy Bargy; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1922 "Just Because She Made Dem Goo-Goo Eyes," John Queen, music by Hughley Cannon; Howley, Haviland and Company, 1900 "Just For the Sake of Your Mother," Lew. Schaeffer and Phil. Leventhal; S and L Music Publishing Company, 1917 "King Chanticleer," A. Seymour Brown, music by Nat. D. Ayer; Jerome H. Remick and Company, 1910 "Dolly," Gabriel Fauré; J. Hamelle, undated "Knick Knocks," Phil Schwartz; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1915 "The Last Part of Ev'ry Party," Joseph McCarthy, music by Harry Tierney; Leo Feist, Inc., 1919 "Lena," Harrison Smith; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1946 "The Lily Rag," Chas. Thompson; Syndicate Music Company, 1914 "The Lily Rag," Chas. Thompson; Syndicate Music Company, 1914 "The Lily Rag," Chas. Thompson; Syndicate Music Company, 1914 "The Little Grey Mother Who Waits All Alone," Bernard Grossman, music by Harry DeCosta; M. Witmark and Sons, 1915 "Love Waltz," Jerome Heller; Church, Paxson and Company, 1911 "Love Will Last," Don Ewell and Harry E. Godwin; Rayster Music Publishing Company, 1967 "Melorose," Marion W. Rose; Willard White Company, 1910 "Mexicali Rose," Helen Stone, music by Jack B. Tenney; M.M. Cole Publishing Company, 1923 "The Minstrel Man," J. Russel Robinson; Melrose Brothers Music Company, 1911 "Miss Chrysanthemum," William Loraine; M. Witmark and Sons, 1901 "Mississippi Rag," W.H. Krell; The S. Brainard's Sons Company, 1898 "Mississippi Rag," W.H. Krell; The S. Brainard's Sons Company, 1898 "The Mouse's Hoofs," Zez Confrey; Exclusive Publications, 1935 "The Music Box Rag," C. Luckyth Roberts; Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1932 "My Cairo Love," Harry D. Kerr, music by John S. Zamecnik; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1919 "My Little Dixie Home," Harrison Smith, music by Ben Garrison; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1929 "My Little Dixie Home," Harrison Smith, music by Ben Garrison; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1929 "My Pet," Zez Confrey; Jack Mills Inc., 1921 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sheet Music, "Napoleon's Last Charge," arranged by E.T. Paull; E.T. Paull, 1910 "Nights of Gladness," Charles Ancliffe; Hawkes and Son, 1912 "Nitric Acid Rag," Ed. Hudson; Stark Music Company, 1922 "Nobody Knows What a Red Head Mamma Can Do," Irving Mills, Al. Dubin and, Sammy Fain; Jack Mills Music Publishers, 1924 "Opera House Rag," Rober R. Darch; The Ragtime Music Publishing Company, 1960 "The Original Jazz Waltz," Mister Jazz; Frank K. Root and Company, 1918 "Our Penthouse on Third Avenue," Lew Brown, music by Sammy Fain; Leo Feist, Inc., 1937 "Pearls," Neil Moret; Jerome H. Remick and Company, 1909 "Poor Buttermilk," Zez Confrey; Jack Mills, Inc., 1921 "Powder Rag," Raymond Birch; Chas. L. Johnson and Company, 1908 "Put it on, Take it off (Wrap it up—Take it Home)," Edgar Leslie and Joe Young; Kalmer and Puck Music Company, 1914 "Ragged Edges," Otto Frey; Victor Kremer Company, 1911 "Ragging the Scale," Edward B. Claypoole; Broadway Music Corporation, 1915 "Rattlesnake Rag," Joe "Finger" Carr and Eddy Hanson; Chatsworth Music Inc., 1952 "Reindeer," Joseph F. Lamb; Stark Music Company, 1915 "Reindeer," Joseph F. Lamb; Stark Music Company, 1915 "The Robin's Departure," Leander Fisher; Century Music Publishing Company, 1914 "The Robin's Departure," Leander Fisher; Century Music Publishing Company, 1914 "Rufenreddy," Roy Bargy; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1922 "Sapho Rag," J. Russell Robinson; Stark Music Company, 1909 "Sapho Rag," J. Russell Robinson; Stark Music Company, 1909 "Satanic Blues," Larry Shields and Emile Christian; Leo Feist, Inc., 1947 "Say Good-Bye to Your Traveling Man," Lew Brown, music by Leo Edwards; Chas. K. Harris, 1913 "Should I," Arthur Freed, music by Nacio Herb Brown; Robbins Music Corporation, 1929 "A Signal from Mars," Raymond Taylor; E.T. Paull, 1901 "Slipova," Roy Bargy; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1922 "Snakey Blues," Will Nash; Pace and Handy Music Company, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Sheet Music, "Some Baby," Jeff Branen, Bobby Heath, and Nat Osborne; The Joe Morris Music Company, 1915 "Songs of the Nation," J. Bodewalt Lampe; Remick Music Corporation, 1907 "Spicy Advice," Ted Courtney and Willie "Bunk" Johnson; Hot Jazz Publishing Company, 1944 "The St. Louis Rag," Tom Turpin; M. Witmark and Sons, 1909 "Step on It," Silvio De Rienzo; Alfred and Company, 1927 "Stop that Bearcat Sadie," Gene Greene; Will Rossiter, 1912 "Stumbling," Zez Confrey; Leo Feist, Inc., 1922 "Taking a Chance on Love," John Latouche and Ted Fetter, music by Vernon Duke; Leo Feist, Inc., 1940 "Temptation Rag," Henry Lodge; M. Witmark and Sons, 1909 "That Clutching Hand," Coleman Goetz, music by Jean Schwartz; Waterson, Berlin, and Snyder Company, 1905 "That Eccentric Rag," J Russel Robinson; I. Seidel Music Publishing Company, 1912 "That Pleasing Rag," J. Fred O'Connor; Harold Rossiter Music Company, undated "That Teasin' Rag," Joe Jordan; Vogel Music Company, 1936 "That's Got 'Em Rag," Wilbur Sweatman; Triangle Music Publishing Company, 1919 "There's a Mother Old and Gray Who Needs Me Now," Geo. H. Diamond; Harold Rossiter Music Company, 1911 "This is Jazz!," Aletha Mae Robinson; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1947 "This is Jazz!," Aletha Mae Robinson; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1947 "Tondaleyo," Aletha Mae Robinson; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1950 "Turn Back the Universe and Give Me Yesterday," J. Keirn Brennan, music by Ernest R. Ball, 1916 "The Turtle Twist," Harrison Smith, music by Ben Garrison; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1958 "The Turtle Walk," Aletha Mae Robinson; Harrison Smith Music Publisher, 1950 "The Two-Two," Arthur N. Green; Jerome H. Remick and Company, 1916 "The Universal Peach Jubilee," H.F. Neilssn; H.F. Neilsson's Music House, 1914 "Watch Your Step," Irving Berlin; Irving Berlin Inc., 1914 "The Weary Blues," Artie Matthews; Melrose Brothers Music Company, 1915 "What A Pity!," Walter Feldkamp; Robbins Music Corporation, 1928 "Where the River Shannon Flows," James I. Russell; M. Witmark and Sons, 1906 "Why Keep Me Waiting So Long?," Tony Jackson; Will Rossiter, 1917 "Whirl Wind Rag," J. Russel Robinson; Melrose Brothers Music Company, 1911 "Yanka Hula Hickey Dula," E. Ray Goetz, Joe Young, and Pete Wendling; Waterson, Berlin, and Snyder Company, 1916 "You Tell 'Em Ivories," Zez Confrey; Mills Music Inc., 1921 "Ziegfeld Follies 1917," Gene Buck and George V. Hobart, music by Raymond Hubbell and Dave Stamper; T.B. Harms, 1917 "Ziegfeld Follies 1918," Gene Buck, music by Dave Stamper; T.B. Harms, 1918 "The Zig Zag," Jack Edwards, Dick Levy, and Willie "The Lion" Smith; Commercial Music Company, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Teddy Wilson, "5 Original Piano Solos by Teddy Wilson," transcribed by Morris Feldman; Leeds Music Corporation, 1942 "Teddy Wilson Piano Creations," Robbins Music Corporation, 1944 "Teddy Wilson Piano Creations," Robbins Music Corporation, 1944 "Teddy Wilson Piano Patterns," Miller Music Corporation, 1939 "Teddy Wilson Piano Rhythms," Leo Feist, Inc., 1937 "Teddy Wilson Piano Rhythms," Leo Feist, Inc., 1937 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - William Russell, "Fugue For Eight Percussion Instruments," New Music Edition, 1933 "Percussion Pieces," New Music Orchestra Series, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Willie "The Lion" Smith, "Contrary Motion," 1958 "Conversation on Park Avenue," Shapiro, Bernstein & Company, 1956 "Between Sharps and Flats," Edwards Music Company, 1949 "Echo of Spring," undated "Fading Star," Mills Music Inc., 1937 "Fussin'," Mills Music Inc., 1937 "I'm Gonna Ride the Rest of the Way," 1948 "Morning Air," Leo Feist, Inc., 1938 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Songbooks, "5 All Star Boogie Woogie Piano Solos," edited by Frank Paparelli; Leeds Music Corporation, 1942 "5 Barrelhouse, Boogie Woogie, & Blues Piano Solos by Mary Lou Williams, edited by Frank Paparelli; Leeds Music Corporation, 1941 "5 Blues Piano Solos by Billy Kyle," edited by Morris Feldman; Leeds Music Corporation, 1943 "5 Boogie Woogie and Blues Piano Solos by Jay McShann," edited by Morris Feldman; Leeds Music Corporation, 1942 "5 Boogie Woogie and Blues Solos by Sammy Price," edited by Frank Paparelli; Leeds Music Corporation, 1943 "5 Boogie Woogie and Blues Solos by The Woody Herman Orchestra," edited by Lou Singer; Leeds Music Corporation, 1941 "5 Boogie Woogie Blues Piano Solos by Pine Top Smith," edited by Frank Paparelli; Leeds Music Corporation, 1941 "5 Boogie Woogie Piano Solos by Pete Johnson," edited by Frank Paparelli; Leeds Music Corporation, 1941 "5 Boogie Woogie Piano Solos by Woody Herman," edited by Lou Singer; Leeds Music Corporation, 1941 "5 'Hot' Novelty Piano Solos by Jimmie Johnson," Clarence Williams Music Publisher, 1933 "5 Piano Solo from Boogie Woogie to the Classics by Hazel Scott," edited by Morris Feldman; Leeds Music Corporation, 1943 "5 Piano Solo from Boogie Woogie to the Classics by Hazel Scott," edited by Morris Feldman; Leeds Music Corporation, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Songbooks, "5 Star Boogie Woogie, Barrelhouse, and Blues Piano Solos," Leeds Music Corporation, 1943 "40 Famous Blues," Melrose Brothers, 1924 "Bessie Smith: Empress of the Blues," Chris Albertson and Gunther Schuller; Frank Music Corporation, 1975 "Blues by Basie," Bregman, Vocco, and Conn, Inc, 1943 "Bob Zurke Delta Rhythms," edited by Morris Feldman; Leo Feist, Inc., 1940 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Songbooks, "Classicanna," Henry Lange; Waterson, Berlin and Snyder Company, 1923 "Count Basie Boogie Woogie Blues," edited by Frank Paparelli; Leeds Music Corporation, 1944 "Count Basie's Boogie Woogie Styles," edited by Buster Harding; Bregman, Vocco, and Conn, Inc., 1939 "Count Basie's Piano Styles," Bregman, Vocco, and Conn, Inc., 1939 "Crosbyana," Mayfair Music Corporation, 1942 "Dizzy Piano," compiled by Gerald Martin; Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1955 "Dorothy Donegan Modern Piano Transcriptions," Robbins Music Corporation, 1945 "Down Beat's 88 Keys to Fame," edited by Sharon Pease; Leeds Music Corporation, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Songbooks, "Down Beat's Styles of Famous 88'ers," edited by Sharon Pease; Leeds Music Corporation, 1947 "E.T. Paull's March Folio," Paull-Pioneer Music Company, 1894 "Earl 'Father' Hines Pianostyles," M.M. Cole Publishing Company, 1936 "Eddie Heywood Modern Piano Transcriptions," edited by Murray Feldman; Robbins Music Corporation, 1946 "Elmer Schoebel's Hot Breaks and Modulations for Piano or Organ," Jack Mills Music Publishers, undated "'Fats' Waller Inimitable Piano Styles," Mayfair Music Corporation, 1934 "Hazel Scott Boogie Woogie Piano Transcriptions," Robbins Music Corporation, 1943 "Inspiration Suite," Willard Robison; Paul Whiteman Publications, 1928 "Jack Mills Modern Folio of Novelty Piano Solos," Jack Mills, Inc., 1922 "Jazzapation: A Study in Jazz by Negro Masters," Alfred Music Company, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Songbooks, "The Library of Ragtime and Early Blues Piano," compiled and edited by Amy Appleby and Peter Pickow; AMSCO Publications, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Songbooks, "Marks Chord Book of 50 Standard Favorites," Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1951 "Mary Lou Williams Boogie Woogie Piano Transcriptions," Robbins Music Corporation, 1943 "Masterpieces in Ragtime," Stark Music Company, 1929 "Negro Classics Syncopated Piano Solos," Clarence Williams Music Publishing, 1925 "Norman Granz' Jazz at the Philharmonic," edited by Quincy Jones; JATAP Publishing Company, 1957 "Novelty Solos for the Piano in Rhythm," Hunter L. Kahler; M.M. Cole Publishing Company, 1934 "The Paramount Book of Blues," The New York Recording Laboratories, undated "Pete Wendling and Max Kortlander Present a Group of Original Compositions for the Piano," Jack Mills, Inc., 1924 "Pianists of Birdland," Chas. H. Hansen Music Corporation, 1958 "Piano Handbook on Boogie Woogie, Blues, and Barrelhouse," J. Lawrence Cook; Capitol Songs, Inc., 1944 "Play Them Rags," Mills Music, Inc., 1961 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Songbooks, "The Ragtime Current," edited by Rudi Blesh; Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1976 "Ragtime Piano," Mills Music, Inc., 1963 "Ragtime Treasures," Joseph F. Lamb; Belwin Mills Publishing Corporation, 1964 "Rural Revelations," Willard Robison; Robbins Music Corporation, 1929 "Sam Fox Popular Standard Rag Folio for the Piano Vol. 1," Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1924 "Sam Fox Popular Standard Rag Folio for the Piano Vol. 2," Sam Fox Publishing Company, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Songbooks, "Sincerely Eubie Blake," transcribed by Terry Waldo; Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1975 "Standard Dance Music Guide," Anthony Ray De Vita, 1944 "Ted Browne Transcription Album," Ted Browne Music Company, 1934 "Thelonious Monk: Revealing Instincts of The Genius of Jazz," transcribed by Hank Edmonds; Jazz Standards Music Company, 1958 "Vincent Lopez Novelty Piano Solos, Folio No. 2," Robbins-Engels, Inc., 1926 "Willard Robison's Six Studies in Modern Syncopation for Piano," Robbins Music Corporation, 1926 Unidentified, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Oversize
  - Articles, 1939-1949 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Esquire's Jazz Book, 1944-1946 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Liner Notes, 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Maps of Chicago, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Metronome, 1946 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Rolling Stone, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Show, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 7)